Vocational Office, 1879 - 1972
Smith College Archives
Vocational Office Records
1879 - 1972
Smith College. Vocational Office.
RG 34.07
61 boxes ( 25 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
The collection is comprised of general office records, fellowship records, recommendations to/for individual students, World War II service opportunity referrals, and Vocational Committee Board of Counselors surveys, questionnaires, and notes.
The first career center at Smith began as the Teachers Registration Bureau "in which alumnae who are teachers or who expect to teach may be registered with full particulars as to their specialties, experience, etc."
In 1917, it was renamed the Appointment Bureau and put under the direction of Helen Wright (Class of 1905). To support the Appointment Bureau, the College also established the Office of the Educational Consultant in cooperation with the Alumnae Association. Members of the Office of the Educational Consultant visited Smith alumnae at their places of employment and developed programming to cultivate students' interest in teaching and academic administration.
In 1925, the office went through a complete reorganization and expansion, and by 1927 it was known as the Personnel Office. The Personnel Office collected data pertaining to the training, academic standing, and the physical appearance of students. For a dollar, seniors could register with the office so that a dossier of complete information would be given to employers including qualifications, employment history, and faculty recommendations. The office also offered academic assessment and advising for students by addressing needs, charting progress and development, and providing post-graduate mentorship. The expansion of the Personnel Office and greater student enrollment figures allowed for students to take part in programs outside the field of education.
In 1933, the Personnel Office was discontinued due to budget cuts. However, with 1,824 students registered, the work was continued under the direction of Marjory P. Nield (Class of 1921) and the name was, again, changed to the Vocational Office. The Vocational Office continued to provide guidance but placed greater emphasis on job placement. During World War II (1939-1945), the office responded to the demands of government agencies and facilitated placement of students into the armed services in addition to their usual programs.
In the mid 70's the Vocational Office was reorganized into the Career Development Office. Today, the Lazarus Center for Career Development provides preparation in undergraduate and post-graduate opportunities as well as individual advising, access to resources, alumnae networking opportunities, and more.
The files are organized into 61 boxes. Boxes 1 through 46 are arranged chronologically by class year. Boxes 47 through 61 are arranged alphabetically by subject; folders are arranged chronologically. The collection is divided into three series.
This collection is organized into three series:
Class Files, 1879 - 1972
General Files, 1922 - 1959
World War II, 1939 - 1945
Records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives except where noted in the finding aid.
The records of the Vocational Office, 1879 - 1972 were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
Smith College. Career Development Office.; Smith College. Vocational Office.; Vocational Guidance -- United States -- History; Women -- Education -- Massachusetts -- Northampton; World War, 1939 - 1945 -- Participation, Female; Smith College. Appointment Bureau.; Smith College. Personnel Office. Placement Division.; Smith College -- History -- Sources.; Vocational guidance -- Massachusetts -- Northampton.; Smith College. Personnel Office. Placement Division.
- Class Files ( 1879 - 1972)
  Includes qualifications, employment history, and faculty recommendations for students from the Class of 1879 though the Class of 1971, as well as deceased alumnae recommendation files.
- General Files (1922 - 1959)
  Includes general office files as well as records on fellowship applicants, financial aid surveys, program assessment, and records from the Board of Counselors Vocation Committee.
- World War II (1939 - 1945)
  Contains records from the Committee Boards, the War Department, the Women's Division and information on service opportunities during World War II.
- Series I: Class Files
  - 1879 - 1896 (Box 1)
  - 1897 - 1900 (Box 2)
  - 1901 - 1902[A-P] (Box 3)
  - 1902[S-Y] - 1903, 1902 - 1903 (Box 4)
  - 1904 - 1905[A-M] (Box 5)
  - 1905[N-Z] - 1906, 1905 - 1906 (Box 6)
  - 1907 (Box 7)
  - 1908[A-H] (Box 8)
  - 1908[I-Z] (Box 9)
  - 1909 (Box 10)
  - 1910[A-R] (Box 11)
  - 1910[S-Z] (Box 12)
  - 1912 - 1913[A-K] (Box 13)
  - 1913[K-Z] (Box 14)
  - 1914[A-N] (Box 15)
  - 1914[O-W] - 1915[A-L], 1914 - 1915 (Box 16)
  - 1915[M-Z] (Box 17)
  - 1916 (Box 18)
  - 1917[A-M] (Box 19)
  - 1917[N-Z] - 1918[A-L], 1917-1918 (Box 20)
  - 1918[M-Z] (Box 21)
  - 1919[A-Mc] (Box 22)
  - 1919[Ma-Wh] (Box 23)
  - 1919[Wo-Z] - 1920[A-L], 1919 -1920 (Box 24)
  - 1920[M-S] - 1921[B], 1920 -1921 (Box 25)
  - 1921[C-K] (Box 26)
  - 1921[L-M] (Box 27)
  - 1921[N-P] - 1922 [A-I], 1921 -1922 (Box 28)
  - 1922[J-Li] (Box 29)
  - 1922[Lo-N] (Box 30)
  - 1922[O-P] - 1923[C-K], 1922-1923 (Box 31)
  - 1923[L-N] (Box 32)
  - 1923[O-P] - 1924[A-K], 1923-1924 (Box 33)
  - 1924 [L-Mi] (Box 34)
  - 1924[Mo-Y] - 1926, 1924-1926 (Box 35)
  - 1927 - 1929 (Box 36)
  - 1930 - 1931 (Box 37)
  - 1932 - 1933 (Box 38)
  - 1935 - 1936 (Box 39)
  - 1937 - 1938 (Box 40)
  - 1939-1945 (Box 41)
  - 1946 - 1949 (Box 42)
  - 1950 -1953 (Box 43)
  - 1954 - 1961 (Box 44)
  - 1962 -1968 (Box 45)
  - 1969- 1972 (Box 46)
- Series II: General Files
  - Counselors-Vocational Committee, 1954 - 1963 (Box 47)
  - Correspondence, 1922 - 1925 (Box 48)
  - Fellowship Applications [H-Ka], 1911 - 1950 (Box 49)
  - Fellowship Applications [Ke-Z], 1916 - 1951 (Box 50)
  - Financial Aid Survey Education, 1935, 1940, 1945 (Box 51)
  - Financial Aid Survey Education, 1950, 1955 (Box 52)
  - Teacher Applications - Agencies, 1917 - 1926 (Box 53)
  - Questionnaire, 1948 (Box 59)
  - Questionnaire, 1950 (Box 60)
  - Questionnaire, 1950, 1952 (Box 61)
- Series III: World War II
  - World War II: Committee Boards, 1939-1945 (Box 54)
  - World War II: Service Opportunities, 1939-1945 (Box 55)
  - World War II: Service Opportunities-War Department, 1939 - 1945 (Box 56)
  - World War II: War Department, 1939-1945 (Box 57)
  - World War II: Women's Division, 1939 -1945 (Box 58)